Welcome to the new feature introduction video of Marvelous Designer 2025.
In the 2025 version, the fabric material type has been newly added to the hair and hair style.
The fabric material type of hair and hair can be used for clothing, braids, and stickers.
Whether you turn on the high-quality rendering display, the hair and hair style effect can be seen.
The hair and hair style can be used in other 3D software through the USB file format.
In the USB file settings, click on the hair and hair data to export the hair and hair.
Next, let's take a look at the various settings related to the hair and hair style.
First, you can change the material type to hair and hair style.
Then, you can adjust the hair and hair properties on this material at the bottom.
There are three options for the shape of the hair and hair.
Round, flat, and line.
You can go to the main menu and set the user's custom 3D hair and hair shape.
Round with thickness and width.
This shape is suitable for checking the overall structure of the hair and hair.
Flat.
A flat shape with thickness but width.
Line.
No thickness, no width curve shape.
Please note that when you turn on the preview hair and hair effect,
due to the need to calculate the hair and hair effect in the 3D window,
the simulation speed may be significantly reduced.
If you need to improve the simulation efficiency,
you can choose whether to turn on the preview hair and hair effect in the 3D display icon.
It is recommended that you only turn on this option when you need it.
If you need to check the hair and hair color randomly,
you can turn on the hair and hair color randomly here.
In addition, when recording or playing animation,
it is strongly recommended that you turn off the preview hair and hair effect,
because it will affect the simulation speed.
Animation in hair and hair is not recorded in real-time animation,
but according to the costume animation recorded in each frame to calculate the hair and hair position.
Next, let's take a look at the hair and hair settings on the fabric.
In the object window, select the fabric type that needs to apply the hair and hair effect.
Then, in the property editor below, change the material type to hair and hair.
Then, in the 3D window, the hair and hair effect will be displayed.
At the same time, there will be various hair and hair settings in the property editor.
You can set the hair and hair settings you need to select.
Let's take a look at the specific usage of these hair and hair settings.
Hair and hair material
The degree of gray is influenced by the degree of gray added to hair and hair.
The higher its value, the darker the gray added to hair and hair.
The lower its value, the lighter the gray added to hair and hair.
The degree of red determines the degree of red in the hair and gray in the hair.
The higher the value, the more red the hair.
The degree of red is based on the ratio of black to orange.
When the black value is 0,
Red will not affect the final result.
The brightness affects the brightness of the hair.
The degree of smoothness affects the texture of the hair reflection.
The higher this value, the stronger the contrast of the hair reflection part, the smoother the hair will look.
When you open the hair change color option, a purple menu will appear at the bottom.
Here you can set the middle and top color of the hair.
The middle color refers to the middle of the hair.
The top color refers to the top of the hair.
You can adjust the position of the middle color by the middle position.
Likewise, you can adjust the position of the top color by the top position.
After opening the insertion, the color of the top, middle, and hair root will naturally change.
The off is no longer the color of the change, but the color of the division of the line.
In the hair shape setting, you can adjust the shape of the hair.
First, let's look at the basic value.
The length is controlled by the length of the hair. The higher the value, the longer the hair.
Thickness is controlled by the thickness of the single hair root hair, the higher the value, the thicker the hair.
The inclination is controlled by theitude of the hair. The higher the value, the more headache it is easy to be influenced.
It's the difference in thickness between the root and the top hair.
The higher the value, the higher the highlight effect.
The more backend you thought of, the better it will be USunderstand the high quality of the hair done in your hair.
On the other hand, the lower the value, the closer the hair at the top and the roots are to each other.
The density affects the density of the hair. The higher the value, the thicker the hair. The lower the density, the thinner the hair.
The number of sections corresponds to the number of sections of a hair.
When the hair is longer and the bend is higher, it is necessary to properly increase the number of sections to ensure the authenticity of the bend of the hair.
On the contrary, when the hair is straighter and shorter, the number of sections will no longer be an important setting.
Basic sticker
Using black and white basic stickers to show different length, thickness, density hair effects on the same piece of hair.
When the base sticker is black, the length, thickness and density are multiplied by 0.
When the base sticker is white, the length, thickness and density are multiplied by 1.
You can create a real hair vinegar effect by using the hair vinegar function next to it.
In this window, you can use the length picture to adjust the hair length distribution, and the bend direction picture to adjust the bend direction of the hair.
In the property setting area of ​​the length picture, you can adjust the hair length distribution according to the needs.
First, you can apply the cutout picture to apply a base picture for the hair length picture.
When there is no cutout picture, the following details are not applicable.
Click on the add icon to add a basic cutout picture.
When the picture is added, it will be combined with the basic gray picture.
Other details can also be adjusted.
The cutout picture will affect the length distribution of the hair by its own brightness or transparency.
Half-transparency and black areas represent the shortest length, while non-transparency and white areas represent the longest length.
The image level is used to set the degree to which the cutout picture is added.
After modifying the number, you can preview the hair length picture effect after the addition.
In the low area, the height of the height is adjusted separately.
The color of the added picture is darker, and the ratio of the length of the lighter area is added.
In the conversion menu below, you can set the length of the folded picture.
The length, width, and ratio of the folded picture are all set.
Next, let's look at the selection settings for the cutout effect.
The higher the intensity of the cutout effect, the more black areas,
it looks like it will form a thin, separated hair.
The random value will affect the random distribution effect of the hair.
The higher the random value, the more obvious the random distribution effect of the hair.
For the curved direction, you can create a combination by setting it with the purple menu.
We will create a suitable cutout by setting it with the purple menu.
The curved direction will increase the hair, so the hair will have a more obvious spiral appearance.
The density of the hair is adjusted by the density of the hair.
The higher the density, the more hair, and each hair is smaller.
On the contrary, the less the number, the larger the size of the hair.
The direction of the intensity random function will make you able to adjust the hair head curved direction.
You can also adjust the number of hair follicles in smaller units through the hair follicle details menu.
When modifying the hair follicle details settings, they will add up to the above properties, but will enhance the effect of each hair follicle.
Increasing the number of hair follicles can make the border of the hair follicle softer and look more natural.
In general, when adjusting the hair follicle effect in the initial stage, you can directly adjust the curve direction to set.
If you are satisfied with the overall hair flow, you need to adjust the direction of the hair follicle in the second stage.
In the third stage, you can adjust the direction of the hair follicle.
By doing this, you can make further adjustments to the hair follicle details.
After clicking on the application, you will see the length next to it.
The black and white length image is applied, and the curve direction is applied to the curve direction image.
Next, let's take a look at the gravity settings.
Gravity, set the gravity of the hair follicle.
After setting the gravity, you will need to change at least one axis value to zero to see the gravity effect.
Next, let's take a look at the gravity settings.
Then, let's take a look at the bending area settings.
The radius, set the radius of the hair follicle.
The higher the value, the bigger the curl of the hair, which makes it fluffier.
The lower the value, the thinner it looks.
The amount is the amount of curls on the hair.
The higher the value, the more hair follicles there are, the lower the value, the less hair follicles there are, which makes it softer.
长度 , 毛发长度分布的不规则程度
数值越高,越不规则, 数值越低,则毛发的长度越均匀
厚度 ,毛发厚度分布的不规则程度
数值越高,毛发的厚度分布越不规则, 数值越低,则越均匀
方向,毛发弯曲方向的不规则程度
The higher the value, the more irregular the bend of the hair. The lower the value, the more even.
Weight, the irregularity of the weight of the hair.
The higher the value, the more irregular the weight of the hair. The lower the value, the more even.
Once again, you must set the weighted value and set the axis,
so that you can see the distribution irregularity of the gravity effect,
curly radius, and control the hair curly radius.
Finally, the random seed distribution.
In the case of seed distribution without changing properties,
try different random arrangement effects through seed distribution.